C. Carlo Fazioli

Curriculum Vitae

Vienna VA
☐ 626.298.1212
☑ cfazzy@gmail.com

I am an applied mathematician and software engineering generalist with experience in cloud computing, AI, and DevOps. I am a lifelong learner with far-ranging interests, confident in my ability to rapidly spin up in new environments, as well as deep-dive into the gritty details.

Current Position

2018 - 2024 Software Engineer, Group W, Inc, Vienna VA

Product manager of, and contributor to, an AI wargaming application developed as a multi-year, multimillion-dollar Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency seedling project between 2019-2021 before transitioning to further development under the Air Force Research Laboratory. Project was awarded the 2021 Military Operations Research Society Barchi prize.

Product management:

- Iterated frequently with client-side management and SMEs to understand evolving priorities.
- Coordinated with client and developers to produce task orders and accurate level-ofeffort estimates.
- Communicated with corporate admins to track budget use.
- Authored monthly status reports and annual final reports.
- Presented at conferences and during networking calls to spread awareness of team efforts.

Cloud-native Architecture:

- Architected microservices and their interfaces.
- Designed two deployment mechanisms: Kubernetes and Docker.
- Managed Kubernetes objects using Helm.
- Defined cloud resource requirements with Infrastructure as Code.

Agile Development:

- Acted as unofficial Agile Team Leader for a team of 10.
- Assembled a robust GitLab CICD Pipeline.
- Facilitated uniform development workflows with a custom Docker image.

Software Engineering:

- Designed Al algorithms under a senior staff guidance.
- Implemented a from-scratch K-medoids algorithm to cluster wargame state data.
- Authored application source code in Python.
- Detailed significant portions of the project in technical documentation.
- Constructed a REST API and Software Development Kit.

System Administration:

- Controlled application access using Azure AD for corporate users, and Keycloak for external users
- Administrated multiple MongoDB instances (each 10GB-1TB)

Education

2006 – 2009 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago IL

2005 – 2006 M.S. Mathematics, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago IL

2000 - 2004 B.S. Mathematics, University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA

Previous Positions

2016 - 2018 Econometric Modeler, International Monetary Fund, Washington DC

Collaborated with IMF economists on global economic model development; researched, designed, and implemented algorithms for use by IMF staff; pursued exploratory research into technology solutions for IMF institutional needs; addressed technical needs of individual IMF staff.

- Researched Monte Carlo techniques to approximate game- theoretical quantities, resulting in substantial runtime improvements
- O Authored user software to assist economists in global systemic risk valuations
- Developed working knowledge of AWS, including IAM, VPC, EC2, and S3, for internal pilot program

2013 – 2016 **Assistant Teaching Professor**, *Dept. of Mathematics*, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Developed course and lab materials; lectured, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources, assigned final grades; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours; directed teaching assistants.

- O Linear Algebra (Fall 2013, Winter 2014, Winter 2015, Spring 2016)
- O Differential Equations (Winter 2014, Spring 2015, Winter 2016)
- Complex Variables and Vector Analysis (Spring 2014)
- O Discrete Math (Summer 2014)
- O Multivariable Calculus, Calculus II, Precalculus, Math 101 (multiple quarters)

2011 – 2013 **Postdoctoral Research Associate**, *Dept. of Mathematical Sciences*, New Jersey Inst. of Tech., Newark, NJ

Researched, designed, and coded novel algorithms for use in fluid dynamics simulations; briefed research supervisor; presented findings to collaborators and conference attendees.

- Surveyed recent research literature
- O Communicated and collaborated with supervisors to develop research program
- O Drafted, wrote, revised, and debugged new numerical algorithms

2011 - 2012 Lecturer, DMS, NJIT, Newark, NJ

Worked with course coordinators to develop course materials; lectured courses, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours.

- O Honors Multivariable Calculus (Spring 2012)
- O Differential Equations (Fall 2011)

2009 - 2011 Lecturer, Dept. of Math, Stats, and Comp. Sci., UIC, Chicago, IL

Worked with course coordinators to develop course materials; lectured courses, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours. Directed teaching assistants in designing and administering discussion sections and quizzes.

- Linear Algebra course coordinator (Spring 2011)
- Differential Equations (Spring 2011)
- O Linear Algebra (Fall 2010, Spring 2010, Fall 2009)
- O Multivariable Calculus (Fall 2010, Fall 2009)

2007 – 2009 Graduate Student Lecturer, MSCS, UIC, Chicago, IL

Lectured courses; wrote and graded exams; assissted students as needed during office hours and scheduled meetings; assigned final grades.

- Linear Algebra (Spring 2008)
- O Multivariable Calculus (Spring 2009, Fall 2007)

2005 – 2009 **Teaching Assistant**, *MSCS*, UIC, Chicago, IL

Led discussion sections; created and graded quizzes; assisted students as needed in office hours and department tutoring center.

- O Calculus II (Fall 2008, Summer 2008, Spring 2005)
- O Calculus I (Spring 2008, Spring 2007, Fall 2006, Spring 2006, Fall 2005)
- Linear Algebra (Summer 2007)
- Calculus I Emerging Scholars Program (Spring 2007, Fall 2006)
- Differential Equations (Summer 2006)
- 2002 **Supplemental Instruction Tutor**, *Dept. of Mathematics*, USF, San Francisco, CA Attended lectures and took notes for undergraduate courses; hosted drop-in peer tutoring sessions
 - Introduction to Statistics (Fall 2002)
 - Calculus I (Spring 2002)

Publications

- M. Booty, C. Fazioli, M. Siegel. "A New Algorithm for Efficient Computation of Moving Fluid Interfaces." (in progress)
- C. Fazioli, D. Nicholls. "Stable Computations of Variations of Dirichlet-Neumann Operators." *Journal of Computational Physics*, Volume 229, Number 3, 906-920 (2010)
- C. Fazioli, D. Nicholls. "Parametric Analyticity of Functional Variations of Dirichlet-Neumann Operators." *Differential and Integral Equations*, Volume 21, Number 5-6, 541-574 (2008)

Invited Talks

- 2023 A Study in Human-Machine Teaming, Trusted AI & Autonomy Defense Technology Review, MITRE, McLean VA
- 2023 An Al-Enabled Wargaming Application for the Cloud, Air Force Research Laboratory Modeling and Reasoning Al Hub, MITRE, McLean VA
- 2023 An Al-Enabled Wargaming Application for the Cloud, Air Force Research Laboratory Project Portfolio Session, Balston VA
- 2014 Overlapping Patches for Dynamic Surface Problems, Conference on Hamiltonian PDE, The Fields Institute for Research in Mathematical Sciences, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada
- 2012 Overlapping Patches for Dynamic Surface Problems, Applied Math Seminar, Department of Mathematics, Drexel University, Philadelphia PA
- 2009 Functional Variations of the Dirichlet-Neumann Operator, IMACS Conference, University of Georgia, Athens GA
- 2009 Functional Variations of the Dirichlet-Neumann Operator, AMS Sectionals Meeting, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana-Champaign IL

Conferences Attended

- 2022 Air Force Research Laboratory Modeling and Reasoning Al Hub Workshop, Online
- 2020 Rigetti Advantage 2020, Sacramento CA
- 2019 IBM Q Summit, Yorktown Heights NY
- 2018 D-Wave Systems Qubits 2018, Knoxville TN
- 2017 D-Wave Systems Qubits 2017, National Harbor MD
- 2014 Joint Mathematics Meetings, Baltimore MD

- 2014 Conference on Hamiltonian PDE, Toronto, Ontario, Canada
- 2012 Frontiers in Applied and Computational Mathematics, Newark NJ
- 2011 Joint Mathematics Meetings, New Orleans LA
- 2009 IMACS Conference, Athens GA
- 2009 AMS Sectionals, Urbana-Champaign IL
- 2009 Joint Mathematics Meetings, Washington DC
- 2005 3-Manifolds and Knot Theory Conference, Austin TX
- 2005 Algebraic Geometry, Symplectic Geometry and Theoretical Physics: A Conference Celebrating the Contributions of Women Researchers, Philadelpha PA

Service

- 2019 2020 Computer Science Intern Team Mentor, Group W and George Mason University, Vienna VA
- 2018 2019 Quantum Computing Intern Individual Mentor, Group W, Vienna VA
- Summer 2015 'Students Tackling Advanced Research' Faculty Mentor, Drexel University, Philadelphia PA
 - 2014 2015 Teaching Innovations Committee Head, Drexel University, Philadelphia PA
 - 2008 2009 Faculty Partner, UIC, Chicago IL
 - Spring 2005 Associate Organizer, Bay Area Math Meet, USF, San Francisco CA
 - Spring 2004 Student Volunteer, BAMM, USF, San Francisco CA

Hobbies and Interests

- Solving the NYT crossword puzzle daily: I am on 401 day streak at the time of this writing!
- O Mindfullness: striving frequent meditator and proponent of mental health.
- Science fiction lit/TV/movies: I'm a fan of classic authors such as Phil K. Dick, contemporary authors such as Neal Stephenson, and the '80s and '90s campiness of movie director Paul Verhoeven.
- Coding competitions: I made it onto the 2021 Advent of Code global leaderboard!
- Cybersecurity: Avid listener of Risky Biz and Darknet Diaries podcasts; amateur malware analyst.